翻译：夏冰雹
翻译：叨叨
翻译：皮诺诺
翻译：奈奈
翻译：绿袖子
校对：绿袖子
后期：迷毁
===BTM字幕组出品===
本字幕仅供交流 切勿商用
唐顿庄园
第四季  第八集
我想Drewe知道我们来了
I assume Drewe knows we're coming.
是的 我昨天送了便条
Yes. I sent a note yesterday.
那些猪好些了吗
So have the pigs recovered, do you think?
刚开始它们有点吓到我
They look in good shape to me,
不过现在好多了
after the shock of their arrival.
可是他怎么不来检查下
But why didn't he check to see
猪夜里饮用的水够不够
... they all had water before he left for the night?
他可能以为把水槽里装满了就行了
Maybe he thought a full trough was enough.
他也没想到这些猪把水槽踢翻了
He wasn't to know they'd kick it over.
Branson先生说的对
Mr Branson is right.
他应该再检查一遍的
He should have made sure.
你也该如此
You would have done.
你知道怎么养猪吗
Where did you learn about pigs?
我们在紫衫农场一直都有养猪 夫人
We've always had pigs at Yew Tree, m'lady.
不是很多 但也足够摸清它们的秉性了
Not many, but enough to learn their ways.
还好你养过
Thank heavens you did.
你找到接管这事的人了吗
So, have you found a man to take over?
还没
Not yet.
不过我想知道 你对这工作感兴趣吗
First, we'd like to know if you'd want the job.
我吗 你指的是我去喂养
Me? You mean I'm to manage
庄园地产上的和我们自己农场的猪吗
the pigs for the estate, as well as my farm?
这要求是多了点
It's asking a lot.
我可以的 如果你们确定的话
I can do it. If you're sure.
我们可以试试 再看怎么继续干下去
Let's give it a try, see how we get on.
我很感激 夫人
I'm very grateful, m'lady.
这是你们家族给我的第二次恩惠了
This is the second good turn I've received from your family,
我只希望有一天可以回报
and I just hope I can pay back a favour one day.
你真的太善良了
How nice of you.
我不知道这算不算恩惠
I don't know if it's much of a favour.
我们给你的活太多了
We're giving you a lot of work.
工作就像老龄
Work's like old age, m'lady.
虽然让人厌恶 但也不可或缺
The worst thing in the world except for the alternative.
是我罢了
It's only me.
我总认为这个问候语
I always feel that greeting betrays
有点自轻自贱的意味
such a lack of self worth.
你今天怎么样
How are we today?
亲爱的 别这样对我说话
My dear, please stop
显着我像个无药可救的孩子
talking to me as if I were a child past hope.
好吧 你现在感觉如何
Very well. How are you feeling?
像Manette医生似得
Like Doctor Manette.
Manette医生-双城记里的人物 在长期囚禁下未老先衰
我要是再不出门
If I don't get out of this house soon,
恐怕我就只记得自己的岁数了
I shall remember nothing but my number.
要不我们下午走去庄园吧
Then why don't we walk to the Abbey this afternoon,
可以吗
if it's fine?
听听Robert的美国之行
Hear how Robert's getting on in America.
那真的是唤作茶壶圆顶绯闻吗
Is it really called the Tea Pot Dome scandal?
1920-1923年在美国发生的著名受贿丑闻
- 听起来不可思议   - 关于什么的
- It seems so unlikely.  - What's it about?
- 还不是老一套 无非是贿赂跟腐败呗
- What is it always about? Bribery and corruption.
拿了好处 允许私企
Taking money to allow private companies
在政府的土地开采石油
to drill for oil on Government land.
Levinson先生的公司是其一吗
Mr Levinson has one of these companies?
我想是如此
I assume so.
你见过他吗
Have you ever met him?
就一次 在当年的婚礼上
Once. At the wedding.
但那一次就足够了
And once was quite enough.
我没法告诉你那有多令人兴奋呢
I can't tell you how thrilling that sounds.
我会等你
I'll be waiting for you.
我们会度过美好的一天
We'll have such a lovely day.
- 那是谁   - 一个朋友而已
- Who was that? - No-one. Just a friend.
你得为义卖多出点力了
You have to pull your weight with the bazaar.
感觉这都成我一人的事了
It seems to have crept up on me.
Robert表哥经常组织这些事吗
Does Cousin Robert usually do it?
是的 村子里的人互相看不顺眼
He does. Half the village hates the other half
只有他能阻止
and he's the only one who can stop them
他们互相斗嘴了
tearing each other's throats out.
真羡慕 这是真手艺啊
I admire that. It's a real skill.
Molesley先生
Mr Molesley, erm,
你曾经做过贴身男仆是吗
is it true that you were a valet?
还是服伺已故的Crawley先生是吗
For the late Mr Crawley?
是的 在此之前是Crawley先生母亲的管家
And butler to his mother before that.
最近我的生活很不顺
I've come down in the world.
你会再爬起来的
You can climb up again.
也许吧 但生活有时会
Maybe. But life kicks the
踢你一脚呢 对吧
stuffing out of you sometimes, doesn't it?
噢 那我可跌下不止一次了
Oh, I've had my stuffing kicked out more than once.
我曾醒来想着这到底有没有意义呢
I've woken and wondered if there was any point to it.
现在呢 我是伯爵夫人的贴身女仆
Yet here I am, lady's maid to a countess.
所以 一切都会好的
So, it can happen.
你现在让我很好奇了
Now you've made me curious.
我也在好奇一些事 你也许能给我答案
I'm curious about something and you could help me.
你知道Bates夫妇吵架了吗
Do you know if Mr and Mrs Bates have had a falling out?
Bates夫妻吗 不大可能吧
Mr and Mrs Bates? That doesn't sound very likely.
你可以把那个机器挪开吗
Can I ask you to put that machine away?
- 我们马上要准备茶了   - 好的
- We'll be laying for tea in a minute. - Of course.
大家都准备好仆人的茶了吗
Is everything ready for the servants' tea?
到底是我一人 还是大家的
Oh, is it just me or do we
花销都比过去多了一倍
have twice the bills we used to?
Ivy 这是你的
Ivy, this is for you.
你找到去除水壶污垢的蛎壳粉了吗
Did you find those oyster shells for the kettle?
我已经放进去了 得等一会 里面都是生水垢
I've put them in. About time. It were full of scale.
那信里到底写的什么啊
What in God's name was that about?
别小题大做 她只是
Don't rise to it. She just
故意想让我们觉得她日子很有趣呢
wants us to think her life's interesting.
有啥趣事吗
Anything interesting?
我在读郡的政报
I'm reading about County Politics.
他们正在招募地方议会的候选人
They're looking for candidates for the local Council.
你怎么不自荐呢
Why don't you put yourself forward?
但我最近没去了解时政 没有把握
But what are my politics these days? I'm not sure.
你总可以了解些的
You could always read a bit about it.
这个房间里你找不到几本
You won't find many books
自由主义思想的书籍
on the Liberal ideals in this room.
更别提关于社会主义的了
And nothing at all about Socialism.
要是你真想明天把我载到瑟斯克
If you're serious about driving me to Thirsk tomorrow,
也许我们可以找到一些那方面的书
perhaps we might find some then.
你现在好多了吗 奶奶
Are you better now, Granny?
你要是来看望过我 你就知道了
If you'd been to see me, you'd know.
别取笑我了 我又不是那照顾人的料
Don't bully me. I'm not up to it.
是啊 Rosamund都告诉我了
No. Rosamund told me.
什么时候 她说什么了
When? What did she say?
你只是需要点关爱罢了
Only that you needed a little cherishing, that's all.
这么说Drewe接受了你提议的工作
So Mr Drewe's accepted your officer.
我很高兴
I'm so pleased.
Drewe一家在紫衫农场做了很多年
The Drewes have been at Yew Tree Farm for many years.
我以为你要说他
I suppose you think
是感情用事的人呢 Blake先生
that's sentimental bosh, Mr Blake.
别为难他 奶奶
Don't be too hard on him, Granny.
Blake先生比他给我们的
Mr Blake has a softer side
第一映象要友善多了
than we first gave him credit for.
在我们启程去伦敦前
I'm relieved to hear I am redeemed
知道你原谅了我真是个宽慰
before we leave for London.
希望你也原谅我
I hope I'm forgiven, too.
我知道你第一次见我时
I know you thought me very snobbish
觉得我很势利
when you first arrived.
我没怪你 我来时
I don't blame you. Given my work,
可是作为国家敌人的特使
I came as an envoy of the enemy.
是我们来早了吗
Are we too early?
保姆 把他们抱进来吧
Bring them in, Nanny.
我想没人介意吧
I don't think anyone will mind.
你爸爸可能会 不过他不在这里 哪来抱怨
Your Papa might, but he isn't here to complain.
等一会 宝贝 妈妈放下杯子
One moment, darling, while Mummy puts away her cup.
来 过来这里 我宝宝 你好啊 小子
Oh, here, let me. Hello there.
对 真乖
Oh, it's all right.
小家伙长得真壮实
He's turning into quite a bruiser.
我得走了
Yes, and I must go.
留下来吃晚餐 妈妈
Stay and have some dinner, Mama.
你不必换晚装
You needn't change.
不了 谢谢 亲爱的 真的不用
No. Thank you, my dear, but no.
你应该要更衣了 我则该走了
You should change and I should go.
你下楼时能不能帮我
When you go down,
带个话给Hughes夫人
can you give a message to Mrs Hughes?
当然好
Of course.
Gillingham昨天打电话过来
Lord Gillingham telephoned today.
明天晚上他想回家之前
He wants to break his journey home.
顺便过来这里
Tomorrow night.
他又来了吗
He'll be here again?
是的 我真不该鼓励他
You're right. I shouldn't encourage him,
可是我想不到别的话叫他不要来
but I couldn't think what to say to persuade him not to.
你会觉得我很懦弱吗
Do you think me very feeble?
不是的 夫人
It's not that, m'lady.
那怎么了
Then what is it?
Anna
Anna?
这不是你该烦恼的事
It's nothing to bother you with.
拜托麻烦我吧
Please bother me.
要是我告诉你 你得保证你听过就罢
If I did, you'd have to promise to do nothing about it.
可这关Gillingham伯爵什么事呢
But how does this concern Lord Gillingham?
不是的 夫人
It doesn't, m'lady.
这跟Gillingham伯爵无关
It's nothing to do with Lord Gillingham himself.
- 那   - 是他的男仆 夫人
- But then...  - It's his man, m'lady.
他的仆人 跟他一起旅行的Green先生
His servant, Mr Green, who travels with him.
噢 天哪
Oh, my God.
- 可是警察应该   - 不可以
- But the police ought to...  - No!
我必须要告诉Gillingham伯爵
I must tell Lord Gillingham.
不 夫人 你答应过的
No, m'lady, you promised.
Bates先生还不知道是他
Mr Bates doesn't know it was him.
但他来的次数越多
But the more he comes here,
Bates先生越有可能发现他是犯人
the more likely it is that Mr Bates will find out.
那我就电话告诉他
Then I'll telephone him and
不要过来了 或者别带Green先生来
tell him not to come, or not to bring Green.
每次Green来这里
I'm frightened every time
跟Bates先生在同一房间时我都很害怕
Mr Green and Mr Bates are in the same room.
你是想他要是猜到了会做蠢事吧
You think, if he guesses, he'll do something.
如果他真那么做了 他们会绞死他的
And if he does, they'll hang him.
或是把他关进大牢 让他永世不能翻身
Or lock him up and throw away the key.
Jimmy 开胃菜可以端上去了
Jimmy, the savouries can go in
Daisy会把沙司送过去
and Daisy'll bring up the sauce.
现在 或许你能解释给我听
And now perhaps you can explain why
为什么你从晚餐时起
you have apparently been under hypnosis
就像被催眠了一样在走神呢
since dinner began.
我不明白您什么意思
I don't know what you mean.
你知道我的意思
Yes, you do.
像树懒一样悠闲地躺在水里
Mooning about like a sloth under water.
说吧
Well?
你知道我早上收到了一封信吗
You know I had a letter earlier?
是Alfred写来的信
It were from Alfred.
好像是他的父亲过世了
It seems his father died
他要回来参加葬礼
and Alfred's coming up for the funeral.
- 我很遗憾   - 还不止这些
- Oh, I am sorry.   - That's not all.
他说他想娶我
He says he wants to marry me.
什么  信里是这么说的吗
What?! Just like that?
他说上次他离开时
He says the way I behaved towards him
我看起来很喜欢他的样子
when he were last here
他希望我们俩之间能有更进一步的发展
made him hope that things had changed between us.
- 你是表现得挺“友好”的   - 还有
- Well, you were very friendly.   - That's not all.
他希望我能离开唐顿  和他一同去伦敦
He wants me to leave Downton and go up to London.
他说他能帮我找到一份工作
He says he can find me a job.
上帝啊
Blimey.
Alfred在信里写了这么多内容
He puts a lot in a letter,
他写得还真多
does Alfred.
开胃菜端上桌了
They're serving the savouries.
这事我们待会儿再说
We'll talk about it later.
现在 把水烧上 准备煮咖啡
Now, er, put the water on for the coffee.
今天做得事情够多了
That's enough for one day, surely.
剩下的明天再做吧
You can finish them tomorrow.
我们散步回村舍吧
Shall we walk back to the cottage?
其他人都准备去睡了
The others are going to bed.
你和Hughes太太说了什么
What were you saying to Mrs Hughes?
就是Gillingham勋爵
Just that Lord Gillingham's asked himself
要再来这里来过夜
for the night again.
他还真是不放手啊
He can't stay away.
是啊  是有点混乱
Yes. It's a bit of a tangle.
你觉得她对他还有好感吗
Do you think she's sweet on him?
他们互有好感
They're sweet on each other,
可是这事没看起来得那么简单
but it's not as simple as that, is it?
现在又加上了Blake先生
Then there's Mr Blake.
我还以为她不喜欢他
I thought she didn't like him.
她起先是不喜欢
She didn't. At first.
总之 他们会处理好他们之间的关系的
Anyway, they can sort it out between them.
Green先生
And Mr Green.
他也会来
He'll be coming back.
你对他没热情了吗
Have you gone off him?
为什么这么说
Why do you say that?
他刚来的时候你非常喜欢他
You liked him so much when he first came.
- 你觉得他很有趣   - 我有吗
- You thought he was funny.   - Did I?
我记不清了
I can't remember.
你对Drewe先生很满意了
So, you're pleased with Mr Drewe?
是的  我也对小猪们很满意
I am. And I'm very pleased with the pigs too.
它们的状态很不错
They're a grand addition.
这些事情都搞定后
When they've settled,
你就可以去忙牛奶场的事了
you ought to consider dairy.
给表现出色的Drewe先生另一份工作吗
Another job for the splendid Mr Drewe.
我认为他表现得确实很出色
I think he IS rather splendid.
看起来他想要把毕生
He seems to want to make farming
都奉献给唐顿的农事上
at Downton his life's work.
这话说得很有腔调
That's very lyrical.
Rosamund Painswick夫人打来电话
Lady Rosamund Painswick is on the telephone, m'lady.
今天有什么安排吗
Do you have anything planned for today?
逛街  就这么多
Some shopping. That's all.
你觉得我应该给他回信吗
Do you think I should write and give him my answer?
如果你考虑好了
If you're sure about it.
我不想嫁给Alfred
I don't want to marry Alfred.
那就没必要多说什么了
Then there's no more to be said.
即使我想 但我还不想现在就把自己束缚住
Even if I did, I wouldn't care to tie myself down yet.
我怎么能知道以后的日子会是什么样的呢
How do I know what life has in store?
你是乐观的一代人 我只能这么说
You're a very optimistic generation, I'll say that.
- 你们在聊什么   - 没什么
- What are you talking about?   - Nothing.
我希望你告诉我
I wish you'd say,
因为很明显你心里藏着事
cos it's clear as day you're up to something.
我们都不知道爸爸什么时候回来
None of us know when Papa's coming back.
不过是的 我们必须在他回来前告诉她
But yes, we must tell her before then.
实际上 我已经有主意了
In fact, I've had an idea.
如果你已经确定了 那为什么不呢
Well, if you're sure, then why not?
Mary的朋友们已经在这里住下了
We've already got friends of Mary staying.
车票订好了再电话联系
Ring with the train time.
“亲爱的 再见”
'Bye-bye dear.'
谁的电话
Who was that?
Rosamund姑妈的
Aunt Rosamund.
她要来探望祖母
She's coming to see how Granny is.
你怎么这么早就下来了
Why are you down so early?
我要在Tom出发去 Thirsk之前
I've got to check some
和他核对好账目数据
figures with Tom before he goes into Thirsk.
越来越像位女实业家了
Quite the businesswoman.
我们要迎接生活发来的挑战
We must rise to life's challenges.
是啊 我想是的
Yes, I suppose we must.
十分钟后咱们在书店见
Let's meet in the book shop in ten minutes.
我有一些信要寄出去  就在那儿见
I've got some letters to post. I'll see you there.
谢谢你
Thank you.
日安
Good day.
别 别这么做
Don't, don't do that.
你没必要这么小心翼翼
You mustn't be so self-conscious.
一个黑人歌手和
A black singer with the
侯爵的女儿在约克郡的小镇上见面
daughter of a marquess in a Yorkshire town?
我们干嘛要这么吸引别人的注意力
Why should we attract any attention?
那是他们的问题
Well, that's their problem.
我们不用理会
It doesn't have to be ours.
你到这儿来让我兴奋得快要窒息了
I'm terribly puffed that you made the journey.
- 我也是 可是   - 可是什么
- Me too, but...   - But what?
我希望我们两人能勇敢地面对这事
I hope we're brave enough for this.
我们当然会
Of course we are!
这不就是让那些心胸狭隘的人们意识到
Isn't it time people knew there are bigger and better
他们应该有更为宽广和
values than the mean-
更为优越的价值观的时候吗
spirited ones they live by?
Grantham夫人知道你今天出来吗
Does Lady Grantham know you're out for the day?
只要我按时回去吃晚餐就没问题
It won't matter as long as I'm back for dinner.
你今晚有演出吗
Are you playing tonight?
有演出的话我就不会来了
I wouldn't be here if I were.
你想让我待多久我就可以留多久
I can stay for as long as you want.
我希望你永远都留在这儿
Well, I want you to stay forever,
可是六点钟就够了
but six o'clock will do.
你今天怎么这么沉默  发生了什么事
You're not very talkative. What's the matter?
我在考虑一些人所处的场合
I was thinking about a couple of people
可能会给他们带来麻烦
who are in a situation which will cause trouble.
这会让他们不快吗
Will it make them unhappy?
不好说
It's hard to say.
这会让某些人不开心
It'll make some people unhappy.
我要煮些咖啡喝  你要来一杯吗
I thought I might make some coffee. Would you like a cup?
不了 谢谢你
No, thank you.
只是咖啡而已  你没必要
It's just coffee. You won't
把自己独立封锁起来
have to surrender any of your independence.
好吧 你赢了
Er, you win.
加牛奶 不加糖
Er, milk but no sugar.
Baxter小姐
Miss Baxter,
我明白你的感受 脆弱的感觉
I do know what it's like, to feel fragile.
我这辈子都挺脆弱的
I've felt fragile my whole life.
现在你也能感受得到 就在这儿
You'll have realised by now that, down here,
我们不怎么喜欢Barrow先生
we don't much care for Mr Barrow,
这话可能有点冒犯你
which may offend you.
我没感觉到冒犯
I'm not...offended.
可我希望你给予我们信任
But I wish you'd give us
让我们对你有个不一样的评价
credit for making up our own minds about you.
你们好
Hello.
这位小姐是
This is Miss...
Bunting 我叫Sarah Bunting
Bunting. Sarah Bunting.
这位是Crawley夫人
And this is Mrs Crawley.
==BTM字幕组出品==
我是在你让我去参加的那个政治集会
I met Miss Bunting at the
上认识Bunting小姐的
political meeting you sent me to.
在里彭的那个
In Ripon.
原来如此
Ah, so that was the reason.
什么意思
Why do you say that?
他对自由主义者的事业
He wasn't exactly enthralled to
并不完全热衷
the cause of the Liberals.
虽然现在我对他的社会主义论
Though I'm not now convinced
- 也不怎么信服   - 为什么不信服
- by his Socialism.   - Why not?
我那时还不知道你是土地中介
I didn't know then that you were the land agent
而且还是
and son-in-law
我们地方乡绅的女婿
of our local milord.
原来我还这么出名呢
I'm surprised I'm so famous.
你不为自己的原则而战吗
Won't you defend your principles?
不 以后再说吧
No, not now.
那我来捍卫  Branson先生
Then I will. Mr Branson
是一位目光锐利的政治思想家
is a keen political thinker.
他毫不畏惧去质疑自己的信仰
He proves this by not being afraid to
这就能证明这点
question his own beliefs.
口才够雄辩
Very eloquent.
我想留下来同您辩论 可我要迟到了
I'd stay to argue, but I'm late.
你住在附近吗
Do you live around here?
我在这儿附近工作
I work here.
在一所学校里
At the school.
很高兴再次见到你
It was nice to see you again.
- 小姐 你好  - 你们好
- Hello, Miss.   - Hello.
她的思想很独立
She knows her own mind.
是的 她确实是这样
Yes, I think she does.
很显然 早餐后
Apparently, he left
他就直接同Dalrymples辞别了
the Dalrymples straight after breakfast,
所以我打电话过去时他已经走了
so I missed him when I telephoned.
- 您已经尽全力了   - 我真的很抱歉
- You did your best.   - I am so sorry.
进来
Come in!
你没穿燕尾服吗 你知道祖母要过来的
No tails? You know Granny's coming.
天啊 她要来吗  我不知道这事
Oh, God, is she? I didn't realise.
算了 别换了
No, don't change.
她也该见识一下现实世界了
It's time she learned about the real world.
这话意味深长啊
A phrase with more than one definition.
我能和你说个事吗
Can I have a word?
我看到一些事情
I've seen something,
可是我不是说这件事有什么不妥当
and I'm not saying there's anything wrong about it,
只是如果我隐瞒了它的话 我会感觉很不舒服
but I'd feel uncomfortable if I kept it to myself.
洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
今天早晨 在瑟斯克  我看到了Rose
This morning in Thirsk,... I saw Rose.
没错 她在逛街啊
Yes, she was shopping.
不 她没在逛街
No, she was not shopping.
她在和一个男人约会
She was...meeting a man.
她伸手抚摸那人的脸颊时刚好被我看到了
I saw her as she reached up to stroke his cheek.
天啊  这次又是和谁
Oh, golly. Who is it this time?
是Jack Ross
It was Jack Ross -
那个请来为你父亲庆生
the singer with the band
的乐队歌手
who came up for your father's party.
就这些  我都告诉你了
Well, that's it. I've told you
其他的就没什么了
and I have nothing more to add.
Anna
Anna?
她已经告诉你了 是吗
She's told you, then?
不要告诉别人 Hughes太太 拜托了
Don't give me away Mrs Hughes, please.
我熬得过去
I can get through it.
我的女仆说你在这里等我
My maid said you were waiting in here.
其他人都在客厅
Everyone else is in the drawing room.
我知道 可是我想你可能想知道
I know, but I thought you'd want to hear.
我想我有办法保住孩子了
I think I know how I can keep the baby.
什么  怎么保
What? How?
有一个佃农
There's a tenant farmer,
他们家一直在为唐顿服务
whose family has been at Downton for years.
我相信他是值得托付的人
I'm sure he can be trusted.
这样风险太大了
This is very reckless.
可 那您什么建议呢
Well, what would you suggest?
我的建议是我们离开这儿
I'd suggest that we go away,
你和我 去远途旅行  无论去哪都行
you and me, on an extended trip to...somewhere.
那么孩子
Then the baby can be
就能被某个国家无子嗣的夫妇收养
adopted by a childless couple in that country,
无论去哪个地方 他们都会喜出望外的
wherever it may be, and they are made very happy.
孩子也会很幸福 你也能
And the baby is happy, and you are...
就算不幸福 至少也是一种解脱
..Well, if not happy, at least free.
可我就不能伴着孩子长大了
But I wouldn't be part of its growing up?
你不能陪伴孩子一生
You wouldn't be part of its life.
为什么说我的主意不可行呢
Why is my idea so reckless?
亲爱的 我该怎么和你说呢
Oh my dear, where shall I start?
如果那个佃农泄露秘密了怎么办
Suppose the farmer talks?
如果有人看到你在他家中出入怎么办
Suppose you're seen visiting his home,
这就是你的主意吗
which I presume is the idea?
如果孩子长得像你
Suppose the baby looks like you
被村民们发现了怎么办
and people in the village notice?
如果是你泄露的呢
Suppose you talk?
我把我需要的东西都写在单子上了
I left a list somewhere that
交给了Patmore太太
I need for Mrs Patmore.
你知道Gillingham勋爵在这儿吗
You know Lord Gillingham is here.
知道  我们刚还聊天的来着
Er, yes. We were just chatting.
我们马上就来
We're coming now.
我太想来管理这个集市了
I'm desperately trying to take control of the bazaar.
可实在是难以取悦大家
Talk about herding cats.
需要的话 我留下来帮你
I'll stay and help if you want.
那你可就要后悔说这话了
You may regret saying that.
趁我在这里 我们可以
And while I'm here, we can
聊聊那个我决定了的计划
discuss a plan that I'd like to get settled.
我一直都想把法语说得更流利一些
I've always wanted to speak better French than I do,
所以我想离开这里几个月
so I thought I'd take a few months off,
去瑞士
go to...Switzerland
切实学习一下
and really learn it.
我明白了  不去法国吗
I see. Not France?
你知道法国就那个样子
You know what the French are like.
而瑞士更干净
While Switzerland is so clean.
他们有一流的医院  就是我们生病了也不怕
And they have wonderful hospitals... in case we get ill.
我们   - 不知道Edith
We?   - I wondered if Edith
是不是也愿意来 陪我做个伴
might like to come. Keep me company.
费用算我的
I'll pay.
你是怎么想的
What do you have to say about that?
我愿意去
I'd like to.
天啊  那好吧 没理由拒绝啊
Goodness. Oh. Well,...why not?
天啊 生活中的惊喜真是无处不在
Golly, life is full of surprises.
可我最好先去确定
But I'd better check to
一下那些小家伙们没有调皮捣乱
see that the young men are keeping the peace.
那我们不告诉她吗
So we won't have to tell her?
我认为没必要 你觉得呢
I don't think we need to, do you?
可你真能支付得起
Can you really afford to
在阿尔卑斯山看四个月小说的花费吗
spend four months reading novels in the Alps?
既然已经做决定了 就没必要再问其他问题了
Why ask the question when the decision has been made?
来吧 我们回到他们中去
Come on, we ought to join the others.
我们上次见面后 你又游历过苏格兰吗
Have you been wandering round Scotland since we saw you?
我来过  我去了Spey
I have. I was on the Spey.
去拜访了堂兄
I did a tour of the cousinage,
然后去艾尔郡参加了一场婚礼
then a wedding in Ayrshire.
我玩得很惬意
I've enjoyed myself.
旅行给了我时间去思考过往
It gave me time to think for once.
有什么与众不同的吗
Oh, what about particularly?
我的人生改变了 我想是这样
My life, I suppose.
有时每个人都应该这样
Everyone should, from time to time.
我可不同意
Oh, I can't agree.
从我的经验来看 这是个危险的职业
In my experience it's a dangerous occupation.
危险
Dangerous?
是的 如果你思考得太多
Well, no life appears rewarding
人生就没喜乐之事了
if you think too much about it.
我听说你最近开始养猪了
I gather you've launched into pigs these days.
是的  它们给了我一份颇具挑战性的工作
Yes. And their arrival was quite the adventure,
这多亏了Blake先生和Mary的英勇之举
in which Mr Blake and Mary were the hero and heroine.
这就是我上次过来时 你没告诉我的事情吗
Is this what you wouldn't tell me when I was last here?
我只是不想为此沾沾自喜
Only because I didn't want to make too much of it.
Mary小姐当时的表现很出色
Lady Mary was perfectly splendid.
Mary小姐一直都很出色
Lady Mary IS perfectly splendid.
Charles 说真的 你也是养猪专家吗
Really, Charles, are you a pig expert, as well?
谢天谢地 还好那晚有他在
He was that night, thank heaven.
Rosamund和Edith有好消息要公布
Rosamund and Edith have some exciting news.
什么消息
What's that?
我么要去度假
We're going on a sabbatical
去真正提升一下我们的法语水平
so we can really improve our French.
我从女家教那儿
The only thing I ever learned
学到的只是怎么说
from my governess was how to say
“请”“谢谢”和“我发烧了”
"Please", "Thank you" And "I have a temperature."
在旅行的时候还是挺有用的
Very useful if one were travelling.
你还记得她吗 妈妈   她总是泪眼汪汪的
Do you remember her, Mama? She was always in tears.
可怜的Mademoiselle
Oh, poor Mademoiselle.
她的生活太复杂了
Her life was full of... complications.
不过 我觉得她倒是乐享其中
I think she quite enjoyed it, though.
你也要去  你不是不想学法语的吗
But why you? You don't want to learn French.
还是借此隐姓埋名
Or is this an incognito
去寻找销声匿迹的Gregson先生吗
search for the missing Mr Gregson?
别戳她的伤心事  这事不能开玩笑
Don't tease her. It's much more serious than that.
谢谢你 Tom
Thank you, Tom.
如果你想知道的话
If you must know,
我只想离开一段时间
I fancy getting away for a bit.
就像Gillingham勋爵一样
Oh. Like Lord Gillingham,
绕着高原思考人生
thinking his way around the Highlands.
我喜欢苏格兰  至少
I like Scotland, me. At least,
我很愿意在那儿生活
I would if I'd ever been there.
我在那吃的一口沙子
Well, I've had a bellyful of heather and no mistake.
你不打算反驳他吗 Hughes女士
Aren't you going to fight back, Mrs Hughes?
Green先生知道他自己喜欢什么
Mr Green can think what he likes.
所以你很期待这次纽约之行了
So you're glad you're on your way to London?
我会尽量忍着不唱出声来的
It'll be all I can do to stop singing when I get in the car.
你去那住哪啊
Where do you live when you're there?
美国纽约州首府
老爷在奥尔巴尼有套房子
His lordship's got a set at Albany.
- 离西部远吗   - 你开玩笑吧
- Is that handy for the West End? - You're joking.
皮卡迪利在这头  塞维尔街在那头
Piccadilly one end, Saville Row the other.
伦敦繁华大街之一
- 噢 幸运的家伙   - 是啊
- Oh, you lucky tyke. - I am a lucky tyke.
Baxter小姐 你喜欢伦敦吗
Do you like London, Miss Baxter?
一般吧
Not particularly.
我曾在那住过一段日子
I lived there at one time
但我并不中意
but it didn't work for me.
你呢 Anna
What about you, Anna?
你倾心于Green先生那样的生活吗
Do you fancy a taste of Mr Green's life?
我在这过的挺好的 谢谢
I'm happy where I am, thank you.
Rose又吵着我要去伦敦了
Rose was badgering me about going up to London again
但她最近去的太频了 你觉得呢
but she's been enough lately, don't you think?
再同意不过了
I certainly do.
毕竟她和我们在一起就是
After all, she's got to
为了多尝试尝试新事物的
have some novelty when we bring her out.
- 这也是   - 她可以帮着管理集市
- Quite right. - She can help with the bazaar.
这样能让她收收心
That'll take her mind off things.
问题是 管理一个成年人
Trouble is, parenting an adult
尤其是别人家的孩子可
especially when it's someone else's daughter
真需要提前商量好才行
is really a matter of mutual agreement.
这样该给她立多少规矩 我至少心里有个数
There's a limit to how much one can simply forbid.
嘘嘘 她来了 事实上 我有话要和她谈谈
Sshh. Here she is. Actually, I want a word with her.
Rose 亲爱的
Rose, darling.
你等会儿能来我房间一下吗
Can I drag you into my room for a moment?
Anna 你能让我们单独谈谈吗
Anna, could you leave us for a minute?
当然
Of course.
你现在睡觉还太早了吧
This is early for you to go to bed.
我今天挺累的
I had rather a tiring day.
我听说
So I heard.
我听说你今天过得很精彩
Well, I heard you had an interesting day.
这到底累不累 我想你应该比我清楚
Whether or not it was tiring, you know better than I.
谁告诉你的
Who told you?
亲爱的 我只是
My dear, all I want
不想让你的生活失控而已
is for you not to lose control of your life.
我爱他
I love him.
我不想听所谓的要同等种族的帝国
And I won't listen to any imperialist nonsense
主义的废话
about racial purity
更别提因为敢于追求梦想就要受到惩罚的事了
and how he should be horsewhipped for daring to dream.
你不明白我的意思吗
Don't you know me better than that?
我要和他结婚 Mary
I'm going to marry him, Mary.
我不在意这要付出什么代价
I don't care what it costs
我是不会藏着掖着的
and I won't keep it a secret.
我一定会告诉我妈妈的
Not once I've told Mummy.
我就是想看到她听到消息那一刹那扭曲的脸庞
I want to see her face crumble when she finds out.
Rose
Rose!
我感觉我们是赶你走似的
I feel we're driving you away.
噢 不是的
Oh, hardly.
我们已经在这待了很长时间了
We're in grave danger of outstaying our welcome.
如果不是Tony提供顺风车的话
If Tony hadn't offered us
我们还不知道要在这赖到什么时候呢
a lift we'd be here forever.
盼望你下次再来拜访
I hope you'll be back soon.
祝你的集市举办顺利
Good luck with your bazaar.
那你不能留下来帮帮我吗
Can't you stay and lend me a hand?
别诱惑我了
Don't tempt me.
我很感激你提出的明智建议
I'm so grateful for your advice and wisdom.
这不仅仅指的是
And not least for
那次有效和满身泥水的救猪事件
the very practical and muddy pig rescue.
乐意为你效劳 小姐
Glad to be of service, m'lady.
你是直接到那吗
Are you going straight there?
我们可能停下来吃午饭
We might stop for some lunch...
谢谢你提供便车
It's kind of you to give them a lift.
这纯属个人原因  我不想
Pure self interest. I
让Charles呆在这 单独和你在一起
couldn't leave Charles here, alone with you.
你下次去南部的时候能来看看我吗
Will you let me see you when you're next down south?
你想说什么 Tony
What would be the point, Tony?
我是不会做你的情人的
I'm never going to be your mistress.
我不会做这样的事的
That's not me at all.
我已经下定决心准备取消订婚了
I've made up my mind to call off the engagement.
- Mabel知道吗   - 还不知道
- Does Mabel know? - Not yet.
从那次以后 我再也没去伦敦
I haven't been in London since...
我应该当面告诉她
and I must tell her face to face.
是应该当面说的
Of course you must,
但我希望你是真的已经考虑好了
but I wish you'd think seriously before you do.
你的意思是想再拒绝我一次
You mean you're going to turn me down again.
我的意思是
I've told you
我不是可以放下这一切的人 Tony
I'm not on the market, Tony.
我不自由
I'm not free.
有时候我也希望我可以 但我不行
Sometimes I almost wish I were, but I'm not.
现在就是这么个情况
And that's all there is to it.
噢 你真是好心
Oh, you have been incredibly kind
谢谢你招待我们这么久
to put up with us for so long.
我们会想你的
We'll miss you.
你们走了 房子都显得空了
The house will seem rather empty.
如果可以的话
If it were my choice,
我真希望可以永远留在这
I should never be away from here.
我能问你一件事吗
Can I ask you one thing?
你对你的那位仆人是什么看法
How do you feel about your man?
我还是不喜欢他 怎么了
I'm still not very keen on him. Why?
我们最好该启程了  所以 真的再见了
We'd better get started. So, this really is goodbye.
希望很快能再见到你
Not for long, I hope.
你把我想说的也给说了
You took the words right out of my mouth.
真遗憾他们走了
I'm sorry to see them go.
你可比不上Mary遗憾
Not as sorry as Mary.
描述爱慕者们的名词都有什么
What's a group noun for suitors?
你说呢  渴望
What do you think? A desire?
爱慕者的渴望  挺好的
A desire of suitors. Very good.
如果你们再胡说八道的话
If you're going to talk nonsense,
我就不理你们了
I have better things to do.
我已经把信寄出去了
I've posted the letter.
那他也有可能会来
Well, he'll probably still come.
不管怎么样
He's got to be
他还是要回约克郡参加葬礼的
in Yorkshire for the funeral, whatever you said.
她对谁说什么了
Whatever she said to who?
噢 就告诉我吧  我知道你藏着秘密
Oh, just tell me. I know you've got a secret,
如果你是为照顾我的心情才这样做
and if you're trying to spare my feelings
这不管用
it's not working.
Alfred写信来了
Alfred's written.
他父亲去世了 所以他要回来安排下葬的事
His father's died, so he's coming for the burial.
他想过来看看我们
He wants to look in and see us all.
是看我们还是看她
See us all, or see her?
Alfred向我求婚了
Alfred's asked me to marry him.
但是她拒绝了
But she's turned him down.
所以这次他的心是彻底碎了
So his heart's broken properly this time.
这样你满意了
Are you satisfied now?
我们就不能不讨论这件事了吗
Why don't we leave the subject there?
我们不想看你们闹翻
We don't want to fall out.
我们不会闹翻的 我们根本就没好过
We can't fall out, we've never fallen in!
所以他们是整整齐齐的离开了呗
So they got off in good order.
我怀疑到底还要多久
I wonder how long it'll take for them
他们才能纷纷向Mary求婚
all to propose to Mary.
Gillingham勋爵不是订婚了吗
Isn't Lord Gillingham engaged?
是这样的 但看得出来
He's supposed to be,
他还是对Mary很感兴趣
but he still seems as keen as mustard.
嗯 这挺有意思的
Well, that is very interesting.
但不是我叫你们来的原因
But it's not why I asked you here.
- 哦   - 不
- Oh? - No.
我是想知道你到底来唐顿干什么
I want to know what you were doing at Downton.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我为什么不能来唐顿  我是在这长大的
Why shouldn't I come to Downton? I grew up here.
看来我要循序渐进一些了
I see I'll have to take the slow path.
你打电话说Edith应该好好被照顾
You telephone to say Edith is to be cherished,
但你没说原因
but you don't say why.
- 没有吗   - 没有
- Didn't I? - No.
接着 你来唐顿拜访 然后在晚餐上说你要和
Next, you invite yourself to Downton and reveal at dinner
Edith要去欧洲大陆
that you and Edith are
待上几个月以便于
retreating to the continent for several months
- 你可以改善你的法语   - 是
- so you can improve your French. - Yes.
Rosamund对学法语不感兴趣
Rosamund has no interest in French.
如果她真的要别人听懂她在说什么
If she wishes to be understood by a foreigner,
她会大吼大叫的
she shouts.
这么说可不公平
That's not fair.
都到这时候了 你们谁不该告诉我实情吗
Isn't it time one of you told me the truth?
如果我告诉你事实是什么
If I told you the truth,
奶奶 我想你就再也不会和我说话了
Granny, you would never speak to me again.
我大概明白是什么情况了
Then you have told me the truth.
但我还是希望你们能说的详细些
But I would like to hear it enunciated more clearly.
好了 现在 我们必须打起精神来
Right. Now, we must all look lively.
今天主子们准备在集市上摆上摊位了
They're starting to set up the stalls for the bazaar today
这需要我们全部出动
and her ladyship will need all hands on deck.
James Molesley先生
James, Mr Molesley,
你们可以也帮着干一些
if you could both keep an eye on things.
- 那我们能有额外的补贴吗   - 没有
- Do we get paid extra? - No,
但如果你干的好的话
but if you play your cards right,
你可以避免被训斥
you'll avoid a clip round the ear.
我要向Patmore女士
I'll ask Mrs Patmore
要一些给村民们的茶点
for some refreshment for the village people.
你要知道 他们会在
This is an early warning that
周六来摆上自己的摊位
they're coming to set up the stalls for Saturday,
所以我们现在最好开始准备三明治和啤酒
so we'd better have sandwiches and beer at the ready.
我所担心的是  Alfred要在
As I feared. Alfred's looking
周六回伦敦
in on Saturday on his way back to London.
所以他有可能会赶上集市
So he'll be here for the bazaar.
他知道他和Ivy没戏了吧
He does know there's no hope with Ivy?
他就是因为这件事写信给我的
Well, that's why he's written to me.
他说他还是想见她一面
But he says he wants to see her.
这对Daisy来说可不好过
It's not going to be very easy for Daisy.
我想给Daisy放一天假好了
I thought I'd give her the day off.
你不介意吧
You won't mind, will you?
你拿主意吧
If you think it best.
反正你是那个要代替Daisy工作的人
It's you who'll do the extra work, not me.
真是的
What a nightmare.
卖冰的那个人病了 所以我要再去找个人
The man selling ices is ill so I've got to find another.
==BTM字幕组出品==
来着伊辛沃尔德和莫尔顿的杂货商有仇
The grocers from Easingwold and Malton
不能安排在一起
can't be side by side,
我还要和Patmore女士讨论今天的菜单
and I've got to decide the house menus with Mrs Patmore.
我来吧  集市的事
I'll do that. Tend to the bazaar.
- 你确定吗 因为你   - 我确定
- Are you sure? Because if you are... - I'm sure.
Robert表叔什么时候回来
When's Cousin Robert coming back?
我不知道 我真希望能知道
I don't know. I wish I did.
我们已经好几天没他的消息了
We've had no word from him in days.
你怎么了
What is it?
我要去告诉大家 要不然我就要疯了
I've got to tell someone, or I'll just explode.
- 告诉谁什么   - 噢 Mary
- Tell someone what? - Oh, Mary.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我订婚了
I'm engaged!
什么事这么着急
But what was so urgent?
第一 今天你能和我一起吃午餐吗
First, can you join me for luncheon today?
噢 行
Well, I suppose so.
不过我要回去告诉Field女士一声 什么事
I ought to go back and tell Mrs Field. Why?
我邀请了Merton大人来
I've got Lord Merton coming.
Mary的教父吗
Mary's Godfather?
嗯 这是很久以前的事了
Mm. It was fixed years ago,
Robert现在出远门了
but now Robert's off on his travels,
Cora太忙了  Mary有别的事
Cora is too busy... and Mary's chucked.
她干嘛去了
For what reason?
她突然之间要去伦敦
Suddenly she has to be in London.
Rosamund不是还在这么
I think Rosamund's still here.
噢 不 她可忍受不了他
Oh, no, she can't stand him.
我可以问问Edith  她应该有空
I could ask Edith. She might be free.
嗯 希望如此
Oh, I hope so.
我是Crawley家族可有可无的一份子
I'm a feeble substitute for the entire Crawley family.
嗯 是 但有你总比没有强
Mmm, yes, but you're better than nothing.
你这么说 我还是挺欣慰的
How warming you make that sound.
噢 太高兴你在这
Oh, I'm ever so glad to find you.
你能帮我弄弄这个吗
Can you help me do these?
为什么这么着急
What's the rush?
Mary小姐要去伦敦
Lady Mary has to go to London.
- 为什么   - 我不知道
- Why? - I'm not sure.
- 但她想我和她一起去   - 当然了
- But she wants me to go with her. - Of course.
你什么时候能回来
When will you be back?
明天晚上 或是再晚点
Tomorrow evening, but we'll be late.
这真不公平
It's not fair.
因为我你没能去纽约
I stop you going to New York
结果现在我可以去伦敦了
and then I set off for London.
别傻了
Don't be silly.
进来
Come in.
Carson先生 我希望我明天
Mr Carson, I'd like to go
可以去约克  我希望你不介意
into York tomorrow. I hope you don't mind.
你在这又没事可做  我为什么会介意
You've got no duties here. Why should I mind?
如果你不反对 我一大早就出发
I'll set off first thing, if you've no objection.
请自便 Bates先生
Be my guest, Mr Bates.
我还是不知道你为什么不去纽约
I still don't understand why you're not in New York,
所以我又能对约克说什么呢
so I can hardly object to York.
玩的开心
Enjoy yourself.
很好 做的好 女士们
Very good. Well done, ladies.
- 我能试试吗   - 现在还不行
- Can I have a go? - It's not ready yet.
至少 你有点矮 不是吗
Anyway, you're a bit of a shrimp, aren't you?
我是矮 但我有肌肉
I'm a shrimp with muscles, me.
我们周六见分晓吧
We'll find that out on Saturday.
我一直不喜欢这些
I've never had a go on one of those.
你不适合玩这些
It's not your sort of thing.
再来些三明治和啤酒
More sandwiches and more beer.
就像是受蝗虫灾了似的
It's like a plague of locusts.
忙吗 Molesley先生
Busy, Mr Molesley?
我喜欢集市
I like the bazaar.
我很享受这个  我希望你也能喜欢
I always enjoy it. I hope you will.
你能帮帮她吗 Molesley先生
Can't you help her too, Mr Molesley?
噢 离远点 你这厚脸皮的家伙
Oh, get off with you, you cheeky devil.
Alfred周六要来 是吗
Alfred's coming Saturday, in't he?
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
我听到你和Hughes女士的谈话了
I heard you and Mrs Hughes talking.
噢 我 我正想 跟你说呢
Well I, I were going to mention it,
因为我觉得你最好避开他
because I wondered if you'd rather be away.
那工作怎么办
What about all the work?
噢 到时候也干的差不多了
Oh, it's mostly done by then.
如果你想避开他 我不介意的
If you'd rather avoid him, I won't mind.
我能去看看Mason先生吗
Could I go and see Mr Mason?
可以啊 这是个好主意
That's a good idea.
去多久都行  注意安全就好
Stay away as late as you like. Just to be safe.
为什么这么着急
But why the urgency?
我说不清楚
I can't explain,
但如果你知道的话 你会明白的
but I swear if you knew, you'd approve.
怎么了 发生了什么
What this? What's happened?
Mary要去伦敦
Mary has to go to London.
没什么事  我明晚就回来
It's no big thing. I'll be back tomorrow night.
- 我能一起去吗   - 不行
- Can I come? - No.
为什么
Well, why not?
因为妈妈需要你在这帮她
Because Mama needs you here.
再见  再见 Rose
Goodbye, then. Bye, Rose.
你想在我那住一宿吗
Do you want to stay at the house?
我可以打电话安排一下
I'll telephone if you do.
行吗  谢谢你
Could you? You're an angel.
我让Mead去他斯温登的姐姐那
I told Mead he could visit his sister in Swindon,
他们尽可能的安排好的
but they'll do the best they can.
谢谢你了
Thank you.
真神秘
How mysterious.
出什么问题了吗
Is anything wrong?
车子不转了 我朋友去找人求救了
The car's packed in, my friend's gone for help.
我帮你看看吧
Would you like me to have a look?
我不想耽误你的时间
I don't want to hold you up.
我也没事  我是去斯基普顿见
I've no appointment. I was on my way to Skipton
供应商比较价格的
to see some suppliers and compare prices.
挺不错的
How impressive.
我以为
I thought that
当代理人成为有钱人的表亲或是女婿的话
when the agent was a cousin or son-in-law,
他就不用再为生活奔波了 反正有别人干
he had free shooting for life, but others did the work.
引用我老婆的奶奶的话
To quote my wife's grandmother,
你一定是读过有关社会主义的报纸的
you've been reading Socialist newspapers again.
你说对了
You should know.
这样好吗
Is this wise?
你可能听过有关于我的故事 但只是一部分
You've heard some of my story, but not all of it.
我以前是在唐顿做司机的
I came to Downton to be the chauffeur.
现在
Now...
可口的午饭
That was a splendid luncheon.
这让我大开眼界了
Quite a change for me.
噢 我才不相信呢
Oh, I can't believe that.
是真的  我吃的简直是病号饭
It's true. I eat nothing but nursery food.
也许你需要一个新的厨师
Perhaps you need a new cook.
这不是厨师的错
It's not her fault.
是我不知道该点些什么
I never know what to order.
人们经常对男人说 你要比老婆先死
A husband is told so often he's going to die first,
否则你是不知道要怎么独自一人生活下去的
you never think you're going to have to manage on your own.
我想Crawley医生还在的话
I doubt Doctor Crawley
他会做的很好
would have managed any better.
我真惊讶他是个医生
I'm so interested he was a doctor.
我曾想自学医术
I wanted to study medicine myself,
但是我父亲真的不认为
but my father didn't really...
不认为这是个绅士的职位
Didn't see it as a profession for a gentleman.
我想他也不至于这么说
I don't believe he'd have gone that far.
但他是确实不认为这是个适合贵族的职位
But he didn't think it quite suitable for a peer, no.
我应该试着举个例子反驳他
I must try and find an example to rebut that.
我该走了
Well, I must be going.
我送你吧 我的车子就停在外面
Let me take you. My car's outside.
我走回去就行
I can easily walk.
请让我载您一程
I'd like to. Please.
那么谢谢了
Then...thank you.
我也得走了
I should go too, Granny.
别走
No. Stay.
我有话想对你说
I want to speak to you.
你结婚的时候还是个司机吗
So were you still the chauffeur when you married?
说来话长
That's a long story.
你的事都是说来话长
Everything with you's a long story.
这个故事有个美好的结局
That one had a happy ending.
至少有段时间是
For a time, anyway.
我知道她死了
I know she died.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
她一定是一个不平常而又独立的人
She must have been a very unusual and independent person.
你说得对
You could say that again.
他们让你留下来
It's nice that they asked you to stay,
在这里谋生是件好事
to make your life here.
我有一个小女儿 这看上去是件正确的事
I have a little daughter, and it seemed the right thing.
这让我对这家人的看法更温和了
Still, it makes me take a kinder view of the family.
你以前对这家人有什么不满意吗
Oh? What do you have against them?
什么都没有
Nothing.
但是 照例 我对他们这类人没什么好感
But, as a rule, I don't really warm to their type.
我不相信人的阶级
I don't believe in types.
我相信人本身
I believe in people.
现在来试试
Now give it a try.
真的很谢谢你  谢谢
I really am very grateful. Thank you.
我不怎么说这个
I don't often say it,
但是Rosamund是对的
but Rosamund is right.
我不知道Drewe先生
I do not know this Mr...Mr Drewe,...
即使他是你说的那样
..But even if he is everything you say,
让孩子留在这
to keep the child here
会像离你脑袋很近的
would be like a permanent
达摩克利斯之剑一样
sword of Damocles, inches from your head.
我无法忍受把他送走的想法
But I can't bear the thought of giving it away.
让他在瑞士长大对不对
And is it right that it should grow up Swiss?
瑞士可以提供一切
Well, Switzerland has everything to offer,...
除了日常对话少了点
..Except perhaps conversation.
但至少缺了也不影响
And one can learn to live without that.
如果Michael出现了呢
And if Michael turns up?
我的建议就是 和他重新开始
Well, if you want my advice, start again.
我会负担一切
Now, I will pay for everything.
Rosamund姨母说她会负担一切
Aunt Rosamund said she would.
事实上你会无法忍受
You'll be quite enough in her debt as it is.
欠她哪怕一分钱
Take any more,
她会开始收严苛的年贡
and she'll start exacting annual tribute.
你的儿子们做什么  我认为他们是有工作的
What do your sons do? I assume they do something.
记得我在晚宴时遇到Larry吗
Remember I met Larry at that dinner?
别提醒我了
Ah, don't remind me.
他们是有工作
They do work.
Larry是银行职员Tim是外交官
Larry's in banking and Tim's in the diplomatic,
没什么令人吃惊的  那你的儿子呢
so nothing very startling there. What about yours?
Matthew是个律师
Matthew was a lawyer.
他辞职了吗
Oh, has he given it up?
他
He's...
他死了
He's dead.
我以为你知道
I thought you would know that.
天呐
Oh, good God.
真的非常抱歉
I'm terribly sorry.
我刚才忘了你是谁
I... I'd forgotten for a moment who you were.
请不要担心
Don't worry. Please.
Mary呢  我以为我今天可以见到她
How is Mary? I do wish I could have seen her today.
虽然慢了些
Well, slow to start with,
但是我很高兴 她走上了正轨
but now she's on her way, which I'm glad of.
- 我听说他们很合适   - 是的
- I heard they were well suited.   - Yes.
他们曾经很幸福 这让分离变得更糟糕
They were happy, which makes the parting worse,
但这样的爱情 最终都会带给人力量
but gives you strength in the end, as we know.
那是你  但不是我
You maybe. Not me.
Mearton女士和我不是刻意要在一起
Lady Merton and I were not exactly meant to be together.
那时候 我们像其他人那样挣扎着活着
We struggled on, of course, as everyone did in those days,
但是我现在不确定它是否明智
but I'm not sure now how sensible it was.
我嫉妒你 你美好的记忆
I envy you, your wonderful memories,
但是我不能觊觎它们
but I can't pretend to match them.
Ross先生还在这么
Is Mr Ross here yet?
- 请问您是谁   - Rose的表姐
- Who shall I say is calling?    - Rose's cousin.
Mary女士
Lady Mary.Huh.
我还在想是不是你
I was wondering if it would be you.
你怎么知道会有人来找你
How did you know someone was coming?
Rose打过电话
Rose telephoned.
她说她告诉了你我们准备确定日期
She said she'd told you we were about to set the date.
我煮了茶  你要来一杯么
I just made some tea. Would you like a cup?
谢谢
Thank you.
我猜你来是想说弗林特郡的老爷
I suppose you're here to say that Lord Flintshire
发现他有个黑人女婿很荒谬
would find the prospect of a black son-in-law preposterous.
您父亲会很赞同
And your father would agree.
说句实在话 比起忍受你的肤色
To be fair to Papa, he'd find your being a band singer
他更难接受你是一个乐队歌手的事实
even harder to swallow than your colour.
Ross先生 你确定吗
Mr Ross, are you sure about this?
婚姻是一项挑战 即使每个人都想要它
Marriage is a challenge, even when everyone wants it.
即使每个人都祈祷你能幸福
Even if everyone prays you'll be happy.
你的意思是在我们这件事上
You mean in our case,
他们一直在努力地拆散我们
they'll all be trying to pull us apart.
每时每刻
Every hour of every day.
告诉我 你觉得她爱你吗
Tell me, do you think she loves you?
你不相信我们吗
Don't you believe in us?
我相信你  但是我不确定她的感情
I believe in you. I'm not so sure about her.
她可能有点爱你 但是我想说
She may love you a bit, but mostly I'd say
她想刺激她的母亲  她恨她
she wants to shock her mother, whom incidentally, she hates.
我的母亲也这么说
That's what my mother said.
她说Rose肯定是想证明什么
She said Rose must be proving some point.
你跟我的母亲有不少共同点
You and my mother have a lot in common.
诚实地告诉我 你觉得
Tell me honestly: Do you
你能挺过他们将对你做的一切吗
think you can survive what they'll do to you?
因为我觉得Rose做不到
Because I don't believe Rose could.
也许你听到这个会安心
It may come as something of a relief for you to hear that
我不会跟Rose结婚
I will not be marrying Rose.
- 你不和她结婚   - 是的
- You won't?   - No.
我曾经分享过她的梦想
I've enjoyed her dreams.
我想她要比你认为的坚强
I think she's more than you allow.
但是
But?
我不想毁了她的生活
I don't want to spoil her life.
我不想让她被人们指指点点和嘲笑
I don't want to watch while people point at her and jeer.
我爱她
I love her.
我希望她幸福
I want her to be happy.
所以你要结束这一切吗
So you'll end it?
是的
Yes.
我本应该早点终止这一切
I should probably have stopped it sooner,
但至少
but at any rate,...
我现在终止了
..I'm stopping it now.
你会告诉Rose吗 还是我去说
So will you tell Rose, or shall I?
我会告诉他的
I'll tell her.
我会给她写封信
I'll write to her.
她明天会收到
She'll get it tomorrow.
但并不意味着我认为这是正确的
It doesn't mean I think it's right.
如果我们生活在更美好的世界里
I wouldn't give in if we lived in even
我绝不会放弃
a slightly better world.
您可能会惊讶 Ross先生
It may surprise you, Mr Ross,
如果我们生活在更美好的世界里
but if we lived in a better world,
我也不愿您放弃
I wouldn't want you to.
夫人 我刚才在楼下
I've been downstairs, m'lady.
他们正在给您做晚饭
They're making dinner for you now.
- 我不想吃太多   - 我告诉他们了
- I don't want a lot.   - I've told them that.
你怎么样了
How are you?
跟昨天差不多
Much as I was yesterday.
跟明天也差不多
Much as I will be tomorrow.
Anna
Anna,
我准备去见Gillingham爵士
I've decided to see Lord Gillingham.
很抱歉 但我不能无所作为
I'm sorry, but I must do something.
我会打电话告诉他我们在午宴时见面
I'll telephone and suggest we meet for luncheon.
我会让他直接解雇他的仆人
Then I'll ask him straight out to dismiss his valet.
我不会说理由
I won't say why.
- 这让我好不安   - 不要不安
- That makes me so nervous.   - Don't be.
不会有人知道原因
No-one needs to know the reason.
Green就不用再回到唐顿了
Green simply won't be back at Downton again.
Bates会怀疑Gillingham爵士
Is Bates going to challenge Lord Gillingham
为什么会换男仆吗
as to why he has a different valet?
我觉得不会
I suppose not.
所以你不用害怕他来访
So you have nothing to fear if he pays us a visit.
他会吗 夫人
And will he, m'lady?
晚餐好了 夫人
Er, dinner's on the table, m'lady.
我不确定Mead会这么做
I'm not sure Mead would have put it like that,
不过还是谢谢了
but thank you.
==BTM字幕组出品==
今天我们装饰了摊位 你们也清楚程序
So, we decorate the stalls today. You all know the drill.
记着
And remember,
所有不完美都会让唐顿面上无光
anything shabby shows Downton in a bad light.
我们不能让这发生
And we can't have that.
对 Hughes夫人 我们不能
No, Mrs Hughes, we can't.
你会来吗
Will you come?
这是个让你
It'll give you a chance
见识村庄的人的机会
to meet a few people from the village.
- 他们不都是些工人吗   - 不 不是
- Is it not just the estate workers?   - Oh, no, no.
地点在教堂义卖市场的后面
The whole area gets behind the Church bazaar.
你要知道你是很幸运的
You're very lucky, you know.
从没有人这么说我 尤其是我自己
Nobody's ever called me that. Least of all myself.
在你一个人们都认识你喜欢你的村庄长大
To grow up in a village where people know and like you,
你的家族受到尊重
where your family's respected.
人们都会欣赏这一点
Plenty would give an eye for that.
我不习惯觉得幸运
I'm not used to feeling lucky.
你应该觉得
Well, you should be.
我们在做色彩搭配吗
Are we trying for a colour scheme?
天呐 我一定会是第一个累倒的
Goodness, I thought I'd be down before anyone.
不  这项任务应该早点开始
Oh, no. This is one task that demands an early start.
帐篷里在准备茶
The tent's up for the tea.
他们正从仓库里搬桌椅
They're fetching tables and chairs from the barn.
不要让他们在接人回来时糟蹋了草地
Don't let them mess up the grass when they drive them back.
Rose   一 二 三 抬
Rose! One, two, three, lift.
我可以的
Oh! I can manage.
Rose  你应该这么做吗
Rose... Should you be doing this?
为什么  你有什么好担心的
Why? What are you afraid of?
怕我会失去这孩子吗
That I'll lose the baby?
看来他们没少让你卖力干活啊
So they've made you a beast of burden now?
是的
That's right.
他们这不是在占你的便宜吗
And they're not taking advantage?
他们准备好了吗  这些给我  James
Are they ready for these? Give me those. James!
能请您把这个带去帐篷吗
Could you take these to the tent, please?
我来介绍一下Bunting女士
May I present Miss Bunting?
她在村庄的学校教书
She teaches at the village school.
我对学校很感兴趣
I'm very interested in the school.
你知道Grantham女士吗
You know Lady Grantham?
当然  很高兴见到您
Of course. It's nice to meet you,
但是我恐怕要上车了
but I'm afraid I must get on.
她是Grantham伯爵夫人吗
So that's the great Countess of Grantham.
是的  也是一个卖力干活的人
It is. Another beast of burden.
如果你坚持 那么我会解雇他
I'll sack him if you insist,
但是告诉我原因  这才公平
but tell me why. It's only fair.
不管这公不公平 但是我不能说
I don't know if it's fair or unfair, but I can't.
一点提示都没有吗
Not even a hint?
如果我能说我会说的
I've said what I can.
他做了些你会觉得可恶的事
He's done something you'd find...abhorrent.
好吧 你赢了
Well, you win.
虽然我不喜欢他 不过这样还是有些卑鄙
But it does seem mean, even if I don't like him very much.
如果你知道真相就不会觉得卑鄙了
You wouldn't think it mean if you knew the truth.
好吧 我相信你
Well, I believe you.
我爱你 我也相信你
I love you and I believe you.
你跟Mabel说了吗
Have you spoken to Mabel?
说了 但我没提那事
I have. But I wasn't going to bring it up.
- 为什么   - 我不想说服你
- Why not?   - I don't want to twist your arm.
我知道除非合你胃口
And I know that you won't make a decision
你才会做决定
until it suits you.
- 她怎么想   - 我很高兴你问了
- How did she take it?   - I'm so pleased you asked.
我想她的答复一定会很有风度
I think the answer is with real style.
我很高兴
Well, I'm glad.
现在可以结账了吗  我恐怕要迟到了
And now, can you get the bill? I'm terribly late.
我必须赶上最后一班车
I must catch the last train.
明天就是教堂义卖了
It's the Church bazaar tomorrow.
我不会放弃的 Mary
I won't give up, Mary.
哪怕你和另一个男人走进礼堂
Not until you walk down the aisle with another man,
很可能那样我也不放弃
and very possibly not even then.
这话让我既闹心又开心啊
I find that both irritating and beguiling in equal measure.
我应该觉得欣慰吗
Should I take comfort from that?
随你怎么想
Take what you like.
我走了
I'm going.
处理一下Green的事
And do what I ask with Green,...
请你完成之后告诉我
..And please let me know when you've done it.
你送给我的吗
You sent for me?
我不会这么做
I wouldn't put it like that.
我还在想你是否有空
I just wondered if you might be free.
悉听尊意
Oh. Your wish is my command.
今天早上Merton爵爷
These came this morning from
送来这些花表示感谢
Lord Merton. As a thank you.
他一贯如此  那我又算什么呢
That was kind of him. But what part do I play in it?
这是给你的
They're for you.
给我的  肯定不是
For me? Surely not.
是给你的 他也送我一些 这是一起送来的
Yes, he sent me some too, these came with them.
我看了卡片
I read the card.
他为他的不得体请求原谅
He asks forgiveness for his tactlessness.
他不得体了吗  他不是故意的
Was he tactless? He didn't mean to be tactless.
- 多好看   - 是的
- How nice.   - Mmm.
非常好看
Very nice.
非常意外 但是非常好看
Quite...quite surprising, but very nice.
我正要去看看他们还需要什么
I'm just going up to see if they need anything more.
能让门童擦一下鞋子吗
Can you leave these for one of the hall boys?
Carson先生 我来做  我不介意
I'll do them, Mr Carson. I don't mind.
你在约克郡待过吗
You took your time in York.
是的 那是段漫长的日子
Yes, it was quite a long day.
- 你做些什么   - 很多事
- What were you up to?   - Oh, this and that.
一 二 三 出发
One, two, three, go!
很高兴再见到你  非常感谢
Lovely to see you again. Thank you very much.
你收到他的信了吗
You got his letter, then?
你真令我失望 Mary
You're so disappointing, Mary.
我以为你明白我 结果你和我妈一个样
I thought you understood, and you're just like my mother.
不 我不像  但是我明白
No, I'm not. But I understand this -
如果你想让你的生活变得复杂
if you're going to complicate your life,
至少要为个正当的理由
do it for the right reasons.
Jeames 我把茶帐篷交给你管
James, I'm putting the tea tent in your charge.
确保茶不会被喝完
Make sure they don't run out of anything.
但是夫人让我们好好玩
But her ladyship said we were to enjoy ourselves.
我们来分析一下
Let us consider this.
她希望你能玩得愉快
She wants you to enjoy yourself,
我希望你管好帐篷
I want you to run the tent.
我们谁可以让你的生活更不便呢
Now, which of us can make your life more uncomfortable?
Molesley先生
Mr Molesley.
Molesley先生  Molesley先生
Mr Molesley! Mr Molesley!
告诉那些人应该把车停哪儿
Tell those people where they're supposed to park.
稍等一下  那是老爷  老爷回来了
Wait a minute. It's his lordship! His lordship's back!
告诉别人 老爷回来了
Tell the others! His lordship's back!
James
James!
你怎么回来了
How can you be here?!
也不说给人打个招呼
Why didn't you send a message?
万一我们手忙脚乱的  你真是过分啊
We would have made such a fuss! You're a beast!
我希望没有太过分
Oh, not quite a beast, I hope.
我只是想给你们个惊喜 现在做到了
I wanted to surprise you and I think I have.
爸爸 你该提前告诉我们的
Papa, you should have let us know!
你什么时候到的
When did you get in?
今天早上  我都忘记有义卖了
This morning. I'd forgotten about the bazaar.
没有打扰你们劳动真是明智之举
I was right not to distract you all from your labours.
Harold叔叔的事怎样了
What happened to Uncle Harold?
他只受了顿训斥
A reprimand, but nothing more.
看来你没有白白赶过去
So it was worth your going.
我觉得我没起到什么作用
I don't think I made a bit of difference,
但就让他们认为我起到了吧
but let's hold on to that fiction.
- 纽约怎么样   - 很有趣
- How was it?  - Interesting.
很现代 很有趣
Very modern...and very interesting.
家里怎么样
How's it been here?
不大有趣也不大现代
Not very interesting and not very modern.
Carson 你好 Bates
Carson. Hello, Bates.
有没有挂念我啊
Have you missed me?
我倒是蛮挂念你们
Because I've certainly missed you.
很高兴您回家 老爷
Good to see you back, m'lord.
你回来了
You're back.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我梦想这一刻多时了
If you knew how many times I'd imagined this scene.
这是个小慰劳  咱们有段时间没见了
This is a treat. It's been a while.
我很抱歉一直没来看你
I'm sorry if I've stayed away.
别抱歉 你不该道歉 别在这里
Nay, no apologies. Not from you. Not here.
你是我的儿媳妇
You're my daughter-in-law,
是我儿子为我留下的唯一的亲人
you're all that I've got left of my son.
不论你回不回来 这儿都是你的家
Whether you come here or not, this is your home.
我每次回来都很高兴
I do love it when I come.
那么我也高兴
I'm glad.
这就是了
That's it.
你在这儿啊 Alfred
Oh, there you are, Alfred.
很高兴见到你 喝杯饮料吧
Nice to see you. Have a glass of this.
- Ivy在吗  - 我在这儿呢
- Is Ivy about?  - I'm just here.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 葬礼怎么样   - 办的不错
- How was the funeral?  - Was well attended.
对我妈也算是个宽慰了
So that's something for my mother to hold on to.
我读了你的信
I read your letter.
如果伤害了你的感情 那我很抱歉
I'm sorry if I hurt your feelings.
该道歉的是我
No, I'm sorry.
我上次过来的时候误会了你的意思
I got the wrong end of the stick when I were last up here,
但这是我的错
but it were my mistake.
你的本意 只是想尽量友好的欢迎我
All you did was...try and give me a nice welcome,
所以你不该抱歉
and you can't feel sorry for that.
你我能以朋友身份道别吗
We can part as friends?
当然可以 我可以做到
We can, as far as I'm concerned.
Daisy在吗
Is Daisy here?
我想知道
I wanted to see if she
我和她能不能继续是朋友
and I could be friends an' all before I go.
她今天去Mason家的农庄了
She's gone to Mr Mason's farm for the day.
直到晚上才能回来
She won't be back till late.
Daisy你今天来是为了避开Alfred吗
Daisy, are you here to avoid seeing Alfred?
Ivy又拒绝了他
Ivy's turned him down again,
所以他以后应该不会回来了
so he won't come back after today.
Patmore太太对此怎么说
What does Mrs Patmore say about it?
让我避开他 所以我就这么做了
To stay away so I don't meet him.
- 我觉得这个想法不对   - 为什么
- I would advise against that.  - But why?
我在这里多待一会你难道不高兴吗
I thought you'd be glad if I stayed a bit longer.
我自然是希望你不会离开
I wish you'd stay and never leave,
我希望有朝一日会这样
and I hope you will one day,
但Patmore太太错了
but Mrs Patmore's wrong.
Daisy 你一生中
Daisy, there won't be
爱上的人不会有很多
too many people that you love in your life,
而他是其中之一
and he's one.
我不知道现在我是怎么想他的
I don't know what I feel about him. Not now.
即使这样 你也要去和这个年轻人道个别
Even so, you need to say goodbye to this young man,
在你们两之间
with nothing jagged,
不要心存遗憾和怨恨
nothing harsh, between you.
我不知道该说什么
I couldn't think of the words.
到时候就知道了
We'll find them together.
我会及时把你送回唐顿
And er, we'll get you back to Downton in time.
你在默默忍受吧
Are you bearing up?
坐这里
In here.
我再也见不到Michael了 是不是
I'm never going to see Michael again, am I?
如果你想去那里找他
If you want to go out there and look for him,
我会支持你
I'll support you.
别人已经找过了
They've already done all that.
警察 私人侦探 能出动的都出动了
Police and private detectives and everything.
那么你必须耐心
Well, then you must be patient.
有时我觉得上帝不愿我幸福
Sometimes I feel that God doesn't want me to be happy.
亲爱的 所有生命都是由麻烦组成的
My dear, all life is a series of problems
我们必须努力解决
which we must try and solve.
一个一个的解决
First one, then the next, and the next,...
直到我们死亡
..Until at last we die.
不如你给咱拿点冰淇淋吧
Why don't you get us an ice cream?
对啊 吃点冰一切就解决了
Yes. That should sort it out.
那不是Gillingham大人吗
Isn't that Lord Gillingham?
怎么 不会吧 他在哪
What? It can't be. Where?
Lane Fox小姐会怎么想啊
What does Miss Lane Fox think about it?
我也很好奇
That's what I wonder.
我同意
I agree.
他是我知道的最不靠谱的未婚夫了
He's the most unconvincing fiance I've ever come across.
她可能不知道
Perhaps she doesn't know.
咱们知道她就知道  这点我很确定
If we know, she knows. You can count on that.
Green怎么会死了呢
Green. But how could he be dead?
我也从别人那里听说的
I'm only telling you what they told me.
他当时在皮卡迪利大街
That he was in Piccadilly and he...
伦敦的繁华街道
然后他滑倒在马路上
slipped or stumbled and fell into the road.
我不知该说什么
I don't know what to say.
咱们昨天刚说完那样的话就出事了
It just seemed so odd after
我觉得很奇怪
our conversation yesterday
我觉得我应该亲自告诉你
that I felt that I should... bring you the news myself.
现在你能告诉我你想让他走人的原因了吗
Can you explain to me now why you wanted him sacked?
不能
No.
你好Tony 天哪
Hello, Tony. Heavens,
今天的集会变得多热闹了啊
what a gathering of the clans today's turning out to be.
我先离开片刻
Would you excuse me for a moment?
我猜你回到唐顿
I don't suppose it's a good sign
是因为出了些不好的事吧
to find you back at Downton?
确实  发生了点事
Not really. Not this time.
你是说他跌倒在路上 然后被车撞了 在昨天
You mean he fell into the road and he was hit? Yesterday?
不是汽车就是卡车
By a bus or lorry, apparently.
有人看到吗
And someone saw this?
人行道上都挤满了  很多人都目睹了
The pavement was crowded. Lots of people saw it.
- 这也算是个解脱   - 为何这么说
- That's a relief.  - What do you mean?
没什么 我只是这么一说
Nothing. I don't mean anything.
Mary
Mary!
你妈妈说过我要来吗
Did your mother warn you I was coming?
她说过
She did.
为什么你这么快又回到约克郡了
Why are you back in Yorkshire so soon?
本来不会这么快
I'd no sooner got back than I was
但我被派到惠特比去参加佃农大会
despatched to a tenant farmers' convention in Whitby.
可会议已经结束了 我准备从这儿回家
But it's over now, so I'll go home from here.
- 我能问你个问题吗  - 当然
- Can I ask you something? - Of course.
- 有点古怪   - 说吧
- It's an odd question.  - Go on.
假设你认为有个人涉嫌犯罪
If you thought a man was involved in a crime,
或是一起事故
or an incident,
但你不责怪他
but you didn't blame him,
你甚至觉得正义在他这边
in fact you thought right was on his side,
你会怎么做
what would you do?
这个问题稍微理论化了些
It's a bit theoretical for an opinion.
- 你不认为他是错的吗   - 是的
- But you don't believe he was wrong? -  No.
看来我所知不多
Well, I'm guessing in the dark,
但要是我 我会守口如瓶
but...I suspect I would say nothing.
这不公平 锤子加重了
That isn't fair. It's weighted.
你来试试吧 Molesley先生 到你了
Go on. You have a go, Mr Molesley.
不了 如果Jimmy都不成 我更没戏
No, no, I won't manage it if Jimmy can't.
试试 我想看
Try. I want to see it.
打得好
Well done!
你作弊了
That was cheating.
这个嘛 靠的只是巧劲罢了
Well, it...it's in the arms.
主要是挥舞 然后就是一点巧劲
It's all to do with the swing, and the swing is in the arms.
你好啊 Baxter女士
So, Miss Baxter,
自我走后都发生过什么 说说吧
anything to tell me about life since I've been away?
没发生什么
No. Nothing's happened.
如果有事情 我会查出来的
I'll find out if it has, you know.
离她远点 Barrow先生
Leave her alone, Mr Barrow.
我们不欢迎海外回来的恶霸
We don't want any bullying brought back from overseas.
是吧 Baxter夫人
Do we, Miss Baxter?
现在 你还想看看其它摊位吗
Now, are there any stalls you'd still like to see?
天哪 终于能在公共场所喝酒了
God, what a relief to be able to drink in public
再也没有警察突击检查了  去他的禁酒令
without a policeman pouncing. Down with Prohibition.
这段时间
You can't mean
你不会是一直都没得喝吧
you never had a drink all the time you were there.
Harold 自有办法
Harold has his uses.
我估计也是
I suppose he does.
希望他两以后别再招惹咱了
And let us hope they both leave us in peace.
我恐怕这希望不大
A slim hope, I'm afraid.
Martha想带他来参加
Martha wants to bring him
明年夏天Rose初次进入社交界的舞会
over next summer for Rose's coming out ball.
为什么
Why?
她说她想
She says she wants
在死前再参加一次伦敦的社交季
to see another London Season before she dies.
你还在 谢天谢地
You're still here. Thank goodness.
我提前赶公车 但还是迟了
I caught an early bus, but it was delayed.
我还以为会错过你
I thought I'd missed you.
Daisy我正要去车站
I'm off to the station now, Daisy.
以后也不回来了
And I won't be back.
我爸爸去世了
My dad's gone and mother's
妈妈搬去去和克鲁郡的姐姐做邻居
moving to Crewe to be nearer my sister,
所以我很高兴你来送我 真的
so I'm glad you're here to say goodbye. I really am.
我给你准备了礼物
I've brought you a present.
Mason先生做的 整整一篮子
Mr Mason's made you a basket full of things.
肉卷 奶酪 火腿 果酱和咸菜
Rolls and cheese and ham, and jams and pickles,
还放了些苹果汁
and he's put some cider in too,
是给你在路上吃的
to keep you going on the train home.
他真好 Daisy
That was kind of him, Daisy.
你确定这些不是给你做的
Are you sure it wasn't meant for you?
不 他是为Alfred准备的
No, he did it for Alfred.
我告诉他我们是老朋友 他就做了这些
I told him we were old friends, so he did it for you.
--你知道Ivy拒绝我了吧   -是的
- You know Ivy turned me down? - I do, yes.
我想我在对待她上有点犯傻
I think I've been a bit blind where she's concerned.
爱情本来就是犯傻
Love is blind.
也许吧 我在想我是不是又做了傻事
Maybe. But I wonder now I've not been a fool.
你对我一直都这么好 这么真诚
You've always been so good to me, Daisy. So true.
可我却一直没注意到
But I could never see it.
谢谢你 我很高兴
That's kind of you to say, and good to hear.
我爱过你 Alfred 我不会否认
I loved you, Alfred. I'll not deny it.
但现在一切都结束了 我们也无法回到从前
But that's done with now, and what I felt won't come back.
是时候你走你的 我走我的了
It's time for you to go your way and me to go mine.
你会祝福我吧
But you wish me well?
是的 我真心祝福你 Alfred
Oh, I do, Alfred, yeah.
那就好 那就很好了
So well. So very well.
永远是朋友
Friends forever.
永远是朋友 Daisy
Friends forever, Daisy.
好的 现在我真的得走了
Right, now this really is goodbye.
你还好吗Daisy
Are you all right, Daisy?
我去储藏室换上围裙
I'll just get this off and pop in the pantry for my apron.
好了 就是这样了
Well, that's that, then.
当你拿出那个篮子
Do you know, when you brought up that basket,...
我真是为你骄傲 差点哭了
..I were so proud of you, I felt like crying out.
就算你是我的女儿
If you were my own daughter,
我也不可能比现在更自豪了
I couldn't be prouder than I am now.
你知道我今天为什么来吗
You do know why I came today.
来看义卖
To see the bazaar.
是来看你
To see you.
令我惊讶的是 我发现 自从我走后
I find - perhaps to my surprise - that since I left,
我就一直想着你
I can't think of anything but you.
我也很惊讶
To your surprise and my surprise.
我只是不想放过机会
I'm only asking for a chance.
真的有会议在惠特比举行吗
Was there really a conference in Whitby?
当然没有
Of course not.
你真让我受宠若惊
I'm flattered,
Charles 还有感动
Charles, and even moved.
但与其再在名单上添加一个对我灰心的男人
But rather than add to the list of men I've disappointed,
现在拒绝你可能会更好些
it might be kinder to refuse you now
你也会释怀些
and let you off the hook.
恐怕我是不会允许你这么做的
Hmm, I'm afraid I couldn't allow that.
至少得让我放手一搏
Not without putting up a fight.
你怎么还在这里啊
What are you still doing here?
我想知道你昨天做了什么
I wish I knew what you were up to yesterday.
- 为什么要出门  - 我只是想出趟门
- Why did you go?   - I wanted to get away.
你没有做什么傻事吧
You'd never do anything foolish, would you?
你绝不会拿我们的一切去冒险吧
You'd never risk everything we've built together?
当然不会 你了解我
Certainly not. You know me.
当我想要做一件事时
When I do a thing, I like
都是会有一个非常充分的理由的
to have a very good reason for doing it.
你们两躲到哪里去了
Where have you two been hiding?
视野良好的地方  魔术师们的最佳藏匿处
In plain view, where all good tricksters hide.
看看我找到了什么  Tom找找看
Look what I've found. Tom, will you see
桌子上还有没有干净酒杯
if there are some clean glasses on that table?
非常好亲爱的 大获全胜啊
Well done, my dear. A real triumph.
但愿吧
I hope so.
我让大家明天再清扫场地
I've told them they can clear up the rest tomorrow.
我觉得这是历史上最好的一次义卖
I thought that was the best bazaar I've known here.
没错 在我们这代人以后最好的
Certainly. At least since your father and I were running it.
现在 我作为一个归家的海外浪人丈夫
And now, as the Prodigal Husband home from the sea,
让我为我的贤妻祝酒
let me raise a glass to my extraordinary wife
她把一切都打理的比我在家时好
who can clearly manage far better in my absence. Cora.
敬Grantham夫人
Lady Grantham.
敬Cora  - 敬妈妈
Cora.  - Mama.
非常出色 Grantham夫人
Very well done, Lady Grantham.
现在我恐怕得走了
And now, I'm afraid, I should be going.
你能来真好
It was so kind of you to come.
我估计这次
I don't suppose I could
- 搭不了你的顺风车了吧 我坐火车来的
- ask YOU for a lift this time?  - I came by train
- 我更喜欢驾车  - 当然
- but I'd much rather drive.  - Certainly.
我送送你们
I'll see you off.
我离开期间
What sort of menage has
到底发生了什么啊
that turned into while I've been away?